<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="florian.loeffler@rrze.uni-erlangen.de">
			IDMone Team
		</author>
		<title>Introduction</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
	
	<section name="Introduction">
			<p>
				At the Regional Computing Centre Erlangen (RRZE) we use the popular MediaWiki
				software (http://www.mediawiki.org/) in many projects for documentation and
				publication purposes.
			</p>

			<p>
				With the development of a Single Sign On infrastructure based on SimpleSAMLphp
				and Shibboleth we needed to make MediaWiki SSO capable in a flexible and easily
				configurable way. We are aware that there are already extensions out there
				providing simple SSO capabilities, but we wanted more.
			</p>

			<p>
				So we started developing the MediaWiki MultiAuthPlugin with the goal to provide
				a single plugin to manage all possible authentication scenarios with one
				single extension -- for example local authentication via original 
				MediaWiki login dialog (as fallback), SSO via Shibboleth, SSO via
				SimpleSAMLphp, and so on.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Description">
			<p>
				The Mediawiki <em>MultiAuth Plugin</em> provides an easily
				configurable way to manage multiple authentication scenarios with
				Mediawiki. This especially includes SSO via Shibboleth and/or
				SimpleSAMLphp.
			</p>
			<p>
				The Mediawiki <em>MultiAuth Plugin</em>
				was developed using Mediawiki 1.18.0 and SimpleSamlPHP 1.8.0 
			</p>
			<p>
				The Mediawiki <em>MultiAuth Plugin</em>
				allows you to
				<ul> 
					<li>use local MW authentication in parallel with external authentication</li>
					<li>completely forbid local authentication - if desired</li>
					<li>configure an external authentication library for SSO
						Currently one of {Shibboleth, SimpleSAMLphp} or both is possible</li>
					<li>auto-create local user accounts if authenticated externally</li>
					<li>auto-update changed user preferences in local user accounts if 
						authenticated externally</li>
					<li>send e-mail notification about auto-created users to a configurable e-mail 
						address</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				If you make the log/ directory writeable the extension also provides a 
				debug.log file to help you identify possible errors.
			</p>
		</section>

		

	</body>
</document>
